Kennedy Collection 1960-2002 (bulk 1963-1992)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Kennedy Collection 1960-2002 (bulk 1963-1992)
MS 575
University of Arizona. Library. Special Collections.
The Kennedy Collection contains media and news clippings related to the Presidency of John F. Kennedy, his wife, Jacqueline Kennedy and family. The bulk of the collection pertains to the Kennedy assassination and materials related to conspiracy theory research and tracing evidence of a cover-up (predominantly newsletters).
15 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series.
Series I: Correspondence, notes, ephemera, photographs and memorabilia, 1962-2001
Series II: Publications and Newsletters (commercial and self-published), 1970-2002
Series III: Newspapers, Magazines, Clippings and Oversize, 1961-2001
Series IV: Audio Visual Materials, 1960-2001
Scope and Content Note
This collection is primarily concerned with the assassination of President John F. Kennedy and the movement to research and prove that the assassination was a conspiracy/cover-up with the aim at finding the truth. The collection includes correspondence, ephemera, newsletters, publications and extensive clippings (magazine and newspaper). The collection documents the subculture of conspiracy theorists and researchers and the manner in which they shared ideas and information through various channels including small shops and self-publishing. This collection also contains audio visual materials including commercial and amateur audio cassettes, VHS tapes, CDs, DVDs and a Super 8 film. There are a limited number of photographs, mostly of the Assassination Symposium on JFK held in 1992. The strongest part of the collection is the runs of newsletters on conspiracy theories including: The Continuing Inquiry, The Third Decade, The Fourth Decade, Echoes of Conspiracy, Grassy Knoll Gazette, Investigator, and Probe. Artificial collection with donations from Gary Opper [bulk], Loretta Cramer and anonymous.
Access Terms
Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.
Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994.
Oswald, Lee Harvey.
Presidents – Assassination – United States – 20th century.
United States –Politics and government – 1961-1963.
United states. Warren Commission. Report of the President’s Commission on the Assassination of President John F. Kennedy.
Political culture – United States – History – 20th Century.
Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994.
Conspiracies – United States – History – 20th century.
Container List
- Correspondence, notes, ephemera, photographs and memorabilia, 1962-2001; Series I
  Mostly materials collected by Gary Opper. His correspondence includes many marketing materials from booksellers, other conspiracy theory researchers, and colleagues regarding the purchasing and trading of information related to the JFK Assassination.
  - Correspondence and photograph, Loretta Cramer, responses from White House on behalf of the President, 1962, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, thank you letter from Jacqueline Kennedy, unsigned, to Loretta Cramer, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, incoming to Gary Opper, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, incoming to Gary Opper, 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, incoming to Gary Opper (continued), 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, incoming to Gary Opper (continued), 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, incoming to Gary Opper, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlet with decorated cover, Kennedy’s Story of Survival, by John Hersey, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets, 1960 Democratic convention and Arlington National Cemetery guide, 1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Pamphlets, The Sixth Floor, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets, JFK Assassination Information Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets, conference catalog, draft of speech and notes, Assassination Symposium on JFK, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Map, North Half of Dealey Plaza, Dallas, People & The Pursuit of Truth, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notes and map, circa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notes, lists, maps, ephemera, 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - JFK 5 cent stamp, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bumper sticker, Ask Congress Who Killed JFK, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Drawing of Jacqueline Kennedy, by Loretta Cramer, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, portraits of JFK and Jacqueline Kennedy, circa 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photographs, rifle and portraits of Penn Jones, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Photograph, Madeline Duncan Brown, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, Assassination Symposium on JFK, Austin and Dallas, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bag with buttons (campaign and conspiracy propaganda), bullets encased in plastic (Mannlicher Carcano) and JFK doll head, 1960s, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Plate with portraits of the Presidents of the USA with JFK in the middle, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Publications and Newsletters (commercial and self-published), 1970-2002; Series II
  This series contains most of the conspiracy theory research and publications. Many of the newsletters series are complete runs. Of special note are the sets of book dealer catalogs.
  - Publication, The Men Behind the Guns, W. R. Morris, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Publication, JFK The Case for Conspiracy, Robert Groden, signed, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Self-published book, Seventy-Six Seconds in Dealey Plaza, R. B. Cutler, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Self-published book, Crossfire, R. B. Cutler, signed, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Self-published book, Evidence of Conspiracy, R. B. Cutler, signed, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Self-published book, Chappaquiddick, R. B. Cutler, signed, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Self-published book, plane crash conspiracies, 2 books, R. B. cutler, signed, 1971-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Self-published book, Mr. Chairman: Evidence of Conspiracy, signed, R. B. Cutler, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript, The Final Cover Up, M & M Bookdealers, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript, Nomenclature of the Assassination Cabal, William Torbitt, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Publication, The Assassination Story, bound clippings, The Dallas Times Herald, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - JFK Assassination Records Collection Act of 1992, Sanders and Zaid, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Proceedings, Second Research Conference on the Third Decade, Rhode Island, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Articles, 1971-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - A Bibliography of Literature relating to the Assassination of Pres. JFK, Library of Congress, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Master Researcher Directory, Gordon Winslow, 1991-1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Catalogs, publishers and booksellers, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Catalogs, M & M Bookdealer (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Catalogs, Prevailing Winds Research, 1991, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Catalogs, The President’s Box Bookshop, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Catalogs, The President’s Box Bookshop, 1991-1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Catalogs, The Last Hurrah Bookshop, Political Assassination, Conspiracy & The Kennedy’s, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Catalogs, The Last Hurrah Bookshop, Political Assassination, Conspiracy & The Kennedy’s, 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Newsletter, The Continuing Inquiry, Penn Jones, Editor, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Newsletter, The Continuing Inquiry, Penn Jones, Editor, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Newsletter, The Continuing Inquiry, Penn Jones, Editor, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Newsletter, The Continuing Inquiry, Penn Jones, Editor, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Newsletter, The Continuing Inquiry, Penn Jones, Editor, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter, The Continuing Inquiry, Penn Jones, Editor, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, The Continuing Inquiry, Penn Jones, Editor, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter, The Third Decade, description of contents, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter, The Third Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter, The Third Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newsletter, The Third Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Newsletter, The Third Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter, The Third Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter, The Third Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter, The Fourth Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter, The Fourth Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter, The Fourth Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Newsletter, The Fourth Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Newsletter, The Fourth Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Newsletter, The Fourth Decade, A Journal of Research on the JFK Assassination, Jerry D. Rose, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter, weekly later named “Echoes of Conspiracy”, Paul L. Hoch, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, Echoes of Conspiracy, Paul L. Hoch, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter, Echoes of Conspiracy, Paul L. Hoch, 1983-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter, Grassy Knoll Gazette, R. B. Cutler, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter, Grassy Knoll Gazette, R. B. Cutler, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newsletter, Grassy Knoll Gazette, R. B. Cutler, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newsletter and photograph of Oswald, 1963, Grassy Knoll Gazette, R. B. Cutler, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter, Grassy Knoll Gazette, R. B. Cutler, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Original mailer, folder, Grassy Knoll Gazette, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter, Coverups!, Gary Mack, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter, The Kennedy Loyalist, Keri Cassidy and Steve Barber, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter, Assassination U. S. A., Ted Gandolfo, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newsletter, The Investigator, G. J. Rowell, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newsletter, The Investigator, G. J. Rowell, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newsletter, The Investigator, G. J. Rowell, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Newsletter, Conflict (The Dorff Report), Robert Dorff, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Newsletter, Assassination Archives and Research Center, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Newsletter, Probe, Citizens for Truth about the Kennedy Assassination, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Newsletter, Probe, Citizens for Truth about the Kennedy Assassination, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Newsletter, Probe, Citizens for Truth about the Kennedy Assassination, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Newsletter, Probe, Citizens for Truth about the Kennedy Assassination, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Newsletter, The Truth Will Prevail, JFK Assassination Information Center, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter, Open Secrets, Assassination Archives & Research Center, Citizens for Truth About the Kennedy Assassination, Committee for an Open Archives, 1994, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, AARC Quarterly, Assassination Archives and Research Center, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Newspapers, Magazines, Clippings and Oversize, 1961-2001; Series III
  Mainstream media with articles on the Kennedy’s, the Assassination of JFK, and stories about conspiracy theories and cover-ups. Includes incomplete runs of LOOK, Life, Time and Newsweek (selected for relevant content). Large collection of newspapers from November, 1963 with front cover stories. The bulk of the clippings from 1961-1963 focus on images of the Kennedy family and contain few articles.
  - Time Magazine, 1963-1975, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Newsweek, 1963-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - New Times, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Skeptic Magazine, 1975, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Four Dark Days in History, Special Publications Inc., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Playboy, Playgirl, Gallery, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Other magazines, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Other magazines (continued), 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Other magazines, 1974-1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Other magazines, 1991-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Comic book, Shade the Changing Man, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clippings, mostly images, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, mostly images (continued), 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, mostly images (continued), 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, larger size, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Magazine clippings, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Magazine clippings, larger size, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Magazine clippings, mostly images, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, photocopies, 1961-1963, circa 2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers, full and partial sections, 1975-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Newspapers, full and partial sections (continued), 1975-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1975-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1988-1995 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings (continued), 1988-1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1993-1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Newspapers and newsletters, includes small run or specialized, 1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Magazine clippings and photocopies, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Magazine clippings and photocopies, 1988-2001 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Magazines and photocopies (continued), 1988-2001 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Life Magazine, oversize, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Life Magazine, oversize, 1966-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Post and Saturday Evening Post, Magazines, oversize, 1963-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Other magazines, oversize, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - LOOK Magazine, oversize, 1962-1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - LOOK Magazine, oversize, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 2 JFK display boars (print and newspaper), oversize, 1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - General Edwin A. Walker campaign materials for governor, oversize, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Magazine clippings, oversize, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers, full or partial copies, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers, front page articles on JFK assassination, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Newspapers, full or partial copies, 1964-1969 (Box 11)
  - Newspapers and weeklies, includes Iconoclast and National Enquirer, 1970-2001 (Box 12)
- Audio Visual Materials, 1960-2001; Series IV
  - Commercial and amateur: audio cassettes, VHS tapes, CDs, DVDs and a Super 8 film, 1 full carton, 1960-2001 (Box 13)